Misiker Tadesse Aga

Research Interests

My research interest is centered around developing techniques and tools that help developers build more secure, reliable, and efficient software. In my PhD thesis, I actively work on developing runtime techniques to provide novel and practical solutions to mitigate advanced code-reuse attacks.

Education

07/2015-Present PhD in Computer Science & Engineering, University of Michigan,

Ann Arbor, MI.

Advisor: Todd Austin

Dissertation Title: Thwarting Advanced Code-reuse Attacks

07/2015–12/2016 MS in Computer Science & Engineering, University of Michigan,

Ann Arbor, MI.

09/2004–07/2008 **BS in Computer Engineering**, *Addis Ababa University*, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.

Professional Experience

07/2015–Present **Graduate Student Research Assistant**, *University of Michigan*, Ann Arbor.

Conduct research in the areas of hardware security, systems security and reliability.

- Developed hardware based solutions to mitigate cold boot attacks and row hammer attacks
- Developed LLVM and GCC based compilation techniques to mitigate code-reuse attacks

05/2017–09/2017 Research Intern, Intel Corp., Hillsboro, OR.

Explored techniques and developed solutions for enhanced vulnerability coverage on an in house tool for automated detection of UEFI BIOS security vulnerabilities.

07/2008–08/2012 **Software Developer**, *Information Network Security Agency*, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.

Designed, developed, and implemented the web based distributed software solutions in team of more than 50 engineers and code-base of more than 100,000 lines of code.

Teaching Experience

07/2010–07/2015 Lecturer, Addis Ababa University, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.

Taught Computer Engineering courses including Computer Architecture, Data Structures, Algorithm Analysis and Design, Digital Signal Processing and Operating Systems.

Technical Skills

Programming:

C, C++, Python, MATLAB, Verilog, Bash, PHP, Java Script Hardware/Software/Tools:

Xilinx Vivado, LLVM, Pin Binary Instrumentation

2260 Hayward Street – Ann Arbor, MI – 48109 \Box +1 (734) 757 0672 • \Box misiker@umich.edu \odot https://web.eecs.umich.edu/ \sim misiker

Publications

- [1] Mark Gallagher, Lauren Biernacki, Shibo Chen, Zelalem Birhanu Aweke, Salessawi Ferede Yitbarek, **Misiker T. Aga**, Austin Harris, Zhixing Xu, Baris Kasikci, Valeria Bertacco, Sharad Malik, Mohit Tawari, and Todd Austin. Morpheus: A vulnerability-tolerant secure architecture based on ensembles of moving target defenses with churn. In *International Conference on Architectural Support for Programming Languages and Operating Systems (ASPLOS)*, 2019.
- [2] Moritz Lipp, **Misiker T. Aga**, Michael Schwarz, Daniel Gruss, Clémentine Maurice, Lukas Raab, and Lukas Lamster. Nethammer: Inducing rowhammer faults through network requests. *arXiv preprint arXiv:1805.04956*, 2018.
- [3] **Misiker T. Aga** and Eneyew Adugna. High performance automatic target recognition. In *AFRICON 2015*. IEEE, 2015.
- [4] **Misiker T. Aga** and Todd Austin. Smokestack: thwarting dop attacks with runtime stack layout randomization. In 2019 IEEE/ACM International Symposium on Code Generation and Optimization (CGO). IEEE, 2019.
- [5] Misiker T. Aga, Zelalem Birhanu Aweke, and Todd Austin. When good protections go bad: Exploiting anti-dos measures to accelerate rowhammer attacks. In 2017 IEEE International Symposium on Hardware Oriented Security and Trust (HOST). IEEE, 2017.
- [6] Misiker T. Aga, Colton Holoday, and Todd Austin. Wrangling in the power of code pointers with proxycfi. In To appear in International Conference on Data and Applications Security and Privacy (DBSec), 2019.
- [7] Salessawi Ferede Yitbarek, **Misiker T. Aga**, Reetuparna Das, and Todd Austin. Cold boot attacks are still hot: Security analysis of memory scramblers in modern processors. In 2017 IEEE International Symposium on High Performance Computer Architecture (HPCA). IEEE, 2017.

Honors & Awards

- o Publication [5] nominated for best paper award at HOST 2017.
- Publication [7] won best demo runner up at C-FAR Semi-Annual Workshop 2017.
- Won Turkish International Cooperation Agency (TICA) scholarship for academically outstanding undergraduate students at Addis Ababa University (2006 2008).

Professional Activities and Services

- Participated in peer-reviewing papers for: SC-2016, DAC-2016/17/18, DATE-2016/17/18, HOST-2018/19, MICRO-2019
- o Research mentoring at Addis Ababa University, Ethiopia (2016-Present)